YungLin Tsun

Industrial Designer

Phillips Ranch, CA

5859576959

☑ YLT.IDesign@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/yltsun/

yunglin.me

Profile

Currently working as sole designer of American Woodmark's stock programs. I have close to a decade of experience in bath furniture products and a proven record of successful products. I breathe trend, design, and value into products that strike great balance with manufacturing capability.

Core Competencies

- Kitchen & Bath Cabinetry Design
- Sanitary Ware Design
- Consumer Electronics Design
- 3D Modeling
- 3D Rendering
- 3D Scan & Print
- Color Development
- Trend & Market research
- Sourcing

Experience

Industrial Designer

2018 - Present

American Woodmark Corporation

- Sole designer in bath product. Including vanity, top, and storage. As well as new finish development in stock programs.
- Lead in successful design proposals that broke major competitor's monopoly in top U.S. home center.
- Lead in design and early engineering of premium products that transforms company's product portfolio. Result in company's first crack at such product category with projected annual sales of \$30~50MM.
- Lead in trend, design, and finish analysis/forecast. My reports have been proven to be on point for years, validated by numerous trade & trend shows.
- Pioneered in company's vanity top program overhaul, and provide collections of new designs that are on trend, better value, and average of ~23% material reduction.

Senior Design Specialist

2015 - 2017

WoodCrafters Home Products, LLC, division of MasterBrand Cabinets Inc.

- Provided designs with excellent value, helped company to gain over 70% of product exposure in the top U.S. home centers.
- Created high quality designs and won 100% product positions in numerous sales events, bring in ~ \$20MM annual sales.
- Increased the sales percentage of new designs by over 20%, keeping company's portfolio on trend.
- Actively engaged with vendors to provide trendy finishes targeted to out clients' audience.

2014 - 2014

WoodCrafters Home Products, LLC, division of Masterbrand Cabinets Inc.

- Successfully developed resources to launch with new designs and won new business over competitors.
- Established first supply network in Asia.
- Engaged with vendors to improve the value of the products by lowering cost & design innovations.

Junior Designer 2011 - 2014

- Provided quarterly design trend & marketing research analysis and helped to win several new programs.
- Created innovative, attracting designs with results of company edging out competitors in numerous product line reviews and gained dominant market share.
- Developed complete system of photo realistic 3D rendering and digital library. Drastically improved ability to sale the designs and reduced R&D resources by eliminating unnecessary prototypes.

Contract Designer

2011 - 2011

Finger Lakes WoodWorks

- Created fully customized high end furniture and cabinetry designs.
- Equipped traditional custom shop with state-of-the-art visualization in realistic 3D renderings.

Freelance Designer

2010 - 2011

- Design consulting, develop graphic, product, and packaging designs for start-ups.
- Generate concept drawings, visualize design concepts, and build production-ready 3D models and / or prototypes.

Instructor 2008 - 2008

Rochester Institute of Technology

- Focused on Rhino3D & Solidworks, provide comprehensive training with exercises on real world products.
- Illustrated work flow to combine of Rhinoceros and SolidWorks to increase design efficiency.

Staff Designer 2003 - 2004

Dragonfly Design

- Created concept sketches, 2D/3D renderings, 3D models, and prototypes.
- One design has become staple product for the client since 2004, and still relevant in sales after 15 years.

Education

Master of Fine Arts, with minor in Art, Craft, and Design Management 2005 - 2010

Rochester Institute of Technology

Scandinavian Furniture Design 2006 - 2006

DIS Studio / Denmark Design Skole

Bachelor of Science 1999 - 2003

National Cheng-Kung University

Certification

- PolyWorks v12 IM + Modeler
- Certified SolidWorks Professional

